we would be dead for sure
if i didn't learn how to code and it's
an invaluable skill that i'll have
in this organization and future
organizations it also just helps me like
think about things like it's a really
great like way to look at the world
sometimes
[Music]
hey you're listening to the sub club
podcast a show dedicated to the best
practices for building and growing
subscription app businesses we'll share
insider secrets from the top
subscription apps on the app stores
let's get into the show
hello i'm your host david bernard and
with me as always revenue cat ceo jacob
hiding
our guest today is seth miller founder
and ceo at rapchat
seth is on a mission to democratize
music creation with rapchat's mobile app
it takes the friction out of making
music and has helped millions of artists
unleash their creativity
on the podcast we talked with seth about
bootstrapping his way to signs of
product market fit
raising money from strategic partners
like sony music and what it's like to
have facebook completely rip off your
app hey seth welcome to the podcast
how's it going thanks for having me yeah
it's been a long time coming you and i
uh first chatted way back in 2019 i you
were like the first office hours call i
ever took at revenue cat so uh oh wow
yeah
go way back in my revenue cat days it
tells you how bad of a uh ceo i am that
we've never actually spoken like on the
phone
in two years or how good david was yeah
i was like sold after one call i'm like
all right dude where do i sign up how do
i get this going
we we have a lot of cross cross
connections because uh you're also
an adjacent portfolio like we nico is a
co yeah i have a co-investor um but then
uh yeah a customer and like we're also
both ohio based so like yeah a lot lots
of cover lots of coverage yeah we got to
hang out so we should i've been thinking
about anyway it's beautiful ohio today
but when i say that you're not going to
make an ohio podcast
[Laughter]
but but maybe um maybe kick off
and tell like what what is rapchat yeah
absolutely so
rapchat is the easiest way to make music
on your phone so we have an ios and
android app
um
you showed me a wrap you made earlier
but you really just like tap in open the
app
we have hundreds and thousands of free
beats on the app so
you just pick a beat you can record over
it and then you can share that anywhere
so
you know we have people making full
length
studio quality songs from their phone
and sharing it to instagram and
soundcloud and then also on platform we
have a social layer as well
which is really cool
but yeah pretty much recording studio in
your pocket
with a community with a social layer
so kind of kind of similar to like a
visco or instagram for music um and our
mission is really to democratize music
uh by providing access and tools to
you know the next billion music creators
how how did you
get on this idea well i mean like a lot
like just scratching my own itch in the
early days so
i mean
almost eight years ago uh when i was in
college uh apps were
really starting to become a thing and
same with social networks and ugc
platforms that you know let you create
content and share it so
you know the day golden era of vine
uh snap
all that um
and there was nothing for music and i
also had a hobby of just freestyling
with my friends so he'd get together
throw on beats and rap
and some people would sing and just
create all sorts of stuff and it's just
something i noticed that was like yeah
this should exist on your phone i should
be able to do this with my high school
buddies that are on a different campus
that i used to do it with and
that was really it just scratching my
own itch and then
over time i think we've really come to
realize that there's just this massive
opportunity to do this at scale for
those that really want to make music and
take it seriously and so
kind of outgrown my own use case a
little bit even though we have people
that come and have fun but really we're
focused on providing tools for the
everyday artists that
historically has been kind of gatekeeped
out of participating in music um and so
we try and give them everything we can
in their pocket um and still feel like
we're only getting started it's not as
easy to pirate logic these days i
imagine it used to be
yeah right what did those early days
look like so like did you learn to code
did you have a coding background did you
um yeah what did those early days look
like and when did you get the app out
yeah i mean pure chaos and it's not too
much different today you know it's just
a little more organized yeah the first
version of the ios app was june 2014
i think it was june 7th and that was
really like wouldn't even pass as an
alpha version today i don't think like
like especially with how good some of
the test flights are but uh you know it
was very basic it was uh you could open
the app
record one track over like 10
pre-defined beats that had to come with
the app store bundle like we didn't even
have server side like sure yeah
uh and
like we just want to test that people do
it and you know of course the first
couple months is just getting friends
off facebook and family to like download
it but then uh started to notice like
you know a little bit of traction and
then more traction and then basically
quit my job i was like all right i gotta
i gotta really go after this and it that
exactly that's when i taught myself how
to code too because i had a lot of help
in the early days just from like friends
faculty members anyone i could get to
like work on it but then after
you know i noticed there's just like
basically early signs of product market
fit i guess if you will now but people
sharing it i was like i really want to
make updates to this thing and i can't
afford any engineers yeah i don't know
anything about fundraising so it was
like the only way i could make any
updates and then wrote really shitty
code for like three years and
but got enough traction and proof to
kind of you know enter the startup space
the fundraising space and now luckily we
have really amazing engineers and i
still write some code here and there
that's probably not that great but uh
you know i i love it so did you have any
co-founders yeah so we i mean we had a
team on campus in the early days uh that
you know we're helping out we've had
a lot of people along the way uh help
out in different parts of the journey
it's been like
an epic journey you know and uh lots ups
and downs but yeah we've had lots of
different people help us out and um now
we have a fully distributed team um
and still relatively small 10 people but
lots of great product builders and yeah
it's a lot of fun yeah david can can
probably talk more to the pain of not
like having
on staff like it's not so much i mean
yeah i mean the cost is a thing for sure
but like i think a bigger thing often is
the the the turnaround time right the
iteration time of not having
well you know even if you're a you know
product person who's non-technical and
you have a technical co-founder there's
even like friction there and
communicating the ideas right if you're
not really in sync and so having that
all in one mind can really like speed
things up and in the early days that's
what it's all about right it's all about
iteration speed it's all about
getting you know different sticking
stuff different stuff to the wall to
like as fast as possible to see what
takes off so uh yeah that's always the
advice i don't know if there's anybody
that listens there probably are people
in the podcast in a similar situation
where they're like maybe they didn't
study programming or whatever like it
it's got to be i mean i don't know so
that you can you can go against this if
maybe it's not the case but it feels
like probably the best way to invest
your time is like get to the basics like
as fast as you can yeah i think so i
mean the amount of time you'll spend
trying to like find a co-founder that
codes if like you know sure the ultimate
is like you find a co-founder you guys
gel and like
they know how to code and you know you
know how to do everything else but like
you
i don't know we would be dead for sure
if i didn't learn how to code and it's
an invaluable skill that i'll have
in this organization and future
organizations it also just helps me like
think about things like it's a really
great like
you know way to look at the world
sometimes oh yeah you're not bamboozled
by engineers too which is nice yeah yeah
and i can like talk to engineers and i
think like it really helps me get
buy-in like i can go to the engineering
team and be like yeah no tell me the
real [ __ ] like you know what's really
going on and we can have technical
combos as opposed to like you know kind
of the
i don't know if it's just uh
whatever stereotype of early ceo that's
like i need this and this is why and i'm
gonna go sell and you know that can get
you into trouble and yeah so anyway i'm
a huge advocate i get some people are
really it's a scary thing to learn it
does take time you're really bad for
ever basically i don't think yeah yeah
you're not going to be good like every
engineer you work with is going to be
like oh
right exactly exactly
but i i do think it's it's really
helpful especially those in the early
days because like trust me you can look
at google and be like oh i need to raise
money for my startup which is what i did
and eventually we did you know do some
fundraising but it's
again the amount of time you spend
trying to figure out how to fundraise
and just jump in this like
really deep ocean
versus you know a skill that you'll have
for life that will instantly
you know provide value in your current
job even yeah i'm all for it i mean i
try to get people to code no matter what
i guess like you mentioned kind of that
that early stage and like
finding product market fit like how long
it's sometimes called wandering the
desert but like how long did you wander
the desert like how long until and then
when you first started to see those
indications
because party market fits this like it's
it's a bad term because like terrible it
means different things to different
people and founders can deceive
themselves all the time
um and and you know even even yc is like
i think one of the best orgs for
defining this and communicating this
their their definition's not very good
right they're like it just feels like
it's going faster it's like okay like
you can still lie to yourself really
easily so what did that look like for
you
yeah no i could not agree more and could
go on
lots and lots of rants about this or
just in general like you know benchmarks
or anything like that
um i think it's
you know and i'll just speak for myself
because like you said it's like totally
different for every company um but the
the first signs is when i remember
i was working the first and only job i
had out of college i was a systems
engineer at progressive insurance so i
was in their data center literally like
working on servers had no idea what i
was doing but
i was there for like six months and i
remember i was like
at work searching twitter like rapchat
on twitter just a term and then over
time like
more and more people just kept sharing
their
tracks to twitter and like saying how
much they love it and then app store
reviews were a big thing i mean it was
just clear that we like like people
truly
loved the product um and that was kind
of the first step and you can't really
like quantify it's not like oh there's a
thousand twitter
it's you know quotes or something you
weren't measuring like day one retention
day 30 retention i was and i learned
that i learned all that stuff over time
and like we track we track a lot of that
stuff but i'm telling you like the most
important stuff was like the qualitative
in the early days um and then
but you need qualitative at scale like
it's not just like your friend you know
it's like uh plus you know 50 000 maus
at that time or whatever it was and i
think that
that was really key like the first thing
is like people were actually able to
record music on their phone and share it
uh some people were really good at it
like this is this is kind of like
obvious now but it wasn't back in the
day like there was like technical
challenges there were you know people
didn't think it would be a thing some
people still don't think it's like a
billion opportunity but like you know we
had to prove out that people would
really record music on their phone like
that was it seemed so obvious what was
the propeller heads app uh gosh what was
that called they've had a few i think um
there was there was i remember that's
bad podcasting i don't know the name of
it but i remember there being some
really key
like music apps that were kind of around
that era right it's like the phones were
finally getting fast enough to be able
to do this without like just falling
over and dying in like yeah
time frame and android's still like
really freaking hard to get right but i
mean over time now we have like a
process of like how we think about you
know does our product work for a certain
market and it's changed like i would say
you never really
we're not in a desert but you never stop
wandering like your product evolves over
time the market evolves over time
we've seen different personas evolve and
grow in our community over time
and now like i said in the early days a
lot of it was providing just like a fun
uh
social media app that was music based
for the ev for everyone and now while we
do have those components it's much more
about providing a really great recording
studio in your pocket with a community
of creators for the everyday artists
like so now we've actually you know
zoned in a little more and focused on
one or two specific segments and we have
really strong metrics engagement uh now
subscriptions for that specific persona
so i think that's a big thing like in
the early days you read all these blogs
and uh you know what to look at for
retention or what to look at for product
market fit but a lot of times it's not
married with context of like personas
and so for the first three years i mean
we're getting whatever millions of
downloads a year
but like this person in
india is here to have fun this person in
georgia is here to take it seriously and
we were just looking at it all blended
and so like once we learned to actually
be like no like now we literally ask
like why are you here like what are your
aspirations and
and then we view things through that
lens that's been one of the biggest
unlocks like
it seems obvious again but um
if you don't think that way then in the
early days you're just kind of like
wondering like well why is my day one
retention like not changing it's like
well you know you're getting 30 of your
users from this like really bad channel
and they're low intent and like you
should filter those out because that's
noise you know i it's so tricky though
because i i was in a similar position
when we were trying to work on growth at
elevate and
um you can you can really easily
that thing where founders are trying to
lie to themselves like it's a very easy
way to lie to yourself right and be like
yeah i have a great retention if i just
ignore all the users with bad retention
right and it's like yeah yeah i think
context is the important thing right
it's like okay like what are the actual
context for this and i mean it makes me
think of um the photoroom uh founder who
we had on a couple a couple weeks ago
um
i don't know the ordering of the podcast
comes out but they also had a similar
situation where they found it like
within their greater user base like a
persona where retention was really
strong intent was really high and then
it's kind of great because it'll gives
you i feel like from a founder and
product perspective it gives you license
to focus right a little bit and be like
okay like we found this profile that's
going to be our most important
and and we're going to like really put
our energy here and it kind of clarifies
a lot of like things for the you know
product decision making well one thing
to interject on this real quick is that
um
i think a lot of people underestimate
just how amazing facebook got at doing
this for founders because
that the feedback loop and
facebook's algorithm and how much data
they had on people prior to app tracking
transparency and apple has kind of
unwound all of this
but that's part of why facebook has
worked as the like
user acquisition
main channel for so many apps to grow
is because all of what you were talking
about jacob and you were talking about
seth
they just do it automatically with
really sophisticated i ai and way more
data than you're ever going to have to
understand people's intent and
the the the types of people who are
going to work
well in your app so when you're feeding
those subscription monetization events
back to facebook and facebook's
experimenting with 50 000 a year money
what are they really doing they're doing
what you can do and now with app
tracking transparency we're gonna have
to do it more is they're finding those
personas and then advertising to get you
that return on on investment and i think
people underestimate how
great facebook did at finding those
amazing personas that work in your app
um but now like it's kind of back to
doing what you've done so
i'd love to hear a little bit more so
you know early on
just seeing it on uh you know rap chat
trending on twitter and like following
all that stuff like i think a lot of
apps over instrument early
and just need to like hit some critical
mass first but then as you get a little
further along
you've talked about building this like
product market fit engine like how
like what's your what's your stack and
then how do you think about
measuring and
learning about those personas and then
kind of building for them and orienting
the app around them i mean there's a lot
there so i mean
again for for context like we are now
just getting into that game which is
like the worst time ever to get into the
game where you know we're actually
trying to
bring those users in with our dollars at
scale maybe but but you know it's it's
been disrupted right so there's
opportunity yeah you'll have probably a
better time than somebody who's trying
to adapt from something they got used to
right we're going the other way pretty
much like so and facebook charged a lot
to do it that's the thing it's like they
captured a lot of that revenue by
figuring it out for you but if you can
figure it out and then find those
channels that reach those personas in a
more cash efficient way you actually are
at a at a better place it's just more
work on your side of things but then you
understand your customers better so
there's benefits too so so maybe seth
put it on a timeline for me so like you
said 2008 or 2009 so you're you're
getting on a a decade of working on this
right it's been it's been
how long have you been working on the
app 20 2013 oh sorry 2017
this is before the podcast sorry i'm
very broadcaster yeah 2013. so still
okay seven eight eight eight years or so
yeah when did when i guess like yeah
when did to kind of lead into david's
question like when did you kind of
transition from like
maybe it's it's recently but like at
some point did you go like okay like how
do i grow this thing like what's the
what's the um
you know i see this happen in a lot of
these consumer apps because consumer
apps really
maybe they're inherently viral but they
almost always have to have something
like to drive the growth right like some
sort of mechanism when did you ever have
a point where you like started to
transition and start to think about that
more
as part of the the company building
yeah absolutely i mean so i mean to date
like you know we've had over 7 million
people create music in over 100
countries and over 80 percent of that's
been organic so it's like
you know we've really
that was our whole thing forever because
we didn't have capital
uh we may have had capital but we didn't
have enough to like even have remotely a
good budget um so we really
yeah we kind of tweaked and refined our
viral loops in the early days because
that's all we had so when i say
scrolling on twitter that was like the
first instance before you could there
was a time period where you couldn't
even post on twitter you had to open the
messages in the app and then we made it
really simple again all this shit's so
obvious now and now every app does it
but you know we made it really simple to
like post a link to your rap chat to
your twitter and your facebook i
remember it's only twitter and facebook
like two ugly square buttons because
those were the things at the time
and that worked though i mean we saw a
10x return on that and i mean to date
you know that type of flow come in
create content share it externally bring
your friends in some of them will either
have the app some of them will go to the
landing page on the website download the
app that loop i mean that's been
millions and millions of downloads so um
you know we're kind of lucky in that
sense that you know being a ugc and
having some network effects like that's
really been key
um and
and just continuing to like improve the
onboarding improve the recording
experience improve the sharing
experience like at some point we you
know added instagram and video where we
auto generated a video for you that was
a really good moment because people and
now that's like our most used feature is
like sharing a video of your track
because those do better on social
network algorithms so i think you know
we've kind of had the core loop
identified for quite some time it's just
been consistently tweaking and investing
and making that better now
uh since we've had that and that's kind
of driven itself and still drives itself
um you know we're looking at all these
different other components as well so
we're testing out some paid stuff um
we're testing out like
different types of like content
marketing and like we have our own
podcast now and we really are bullish on
like you know creating educational
content for the mass music maker across
different channels and think we can do
some really cool stuff there
so we're starting to explore different
parts of like the growth stack um and
you know even web like seo and web we
haven't invested in and we think it's a
huge opportunity because we want to
expose this content to
to everyone and we can create unique
experiences per platform and we have the
bandwidth to do it now so
now it's kind of the fun part um whereas
you know before it was yeah pretty much
all organic yeah how did you make money
with the app like throughout the history
and when did you realize subscriptions
were the only and best way to make money
on the app store
yeah
nice plug
no i mean we didn't it's we didn't make
money forever like until last year i
think we hit like we're hitting year one
so we'll
figure out these yearly renewal renewals
and all that but um yeah we didn't make
money like we basically
punted making money jury's still out
like i think if i were to start another
app company i would just implement
subscriptions way earlier but um you
know this is what when we started and we
raised our first round of funding so
we've raised you know three rounds of
funding and when did you raise your
first round first year was 2017 and it
was very much like of course the
investors are like no no no don't make
money you know
grow your user base do what twitter did
and then you can always make it i've got
some right here yeah just keep raising
venture capital yeah yeah essentially
like just get on the treadmill of mau's
and then at some point you can do an
advertising layer and that's how it's
done like that's that's
and you know it's not like we had any
much better ideas either and we're like
all right like yeah let's just keep
growing the user base how did you get
how did you get this four years were you
just like eating ramen and and working
side jobs and stuff yeah dude yeah yeah
i mean so two of them were in colleges
like part-time you know like grinding
it took a minute just to get the test
flight out and then the first version
then
after progressive i for a year you know
i just
i mean i cashed out my 401k and made
some decent money at progressive and
sold bitcoin at like 250 a coin
yeah things like that so nice that was
great uh maxed out some credit cards i
mean whatever though you do what you got
to do right i was surviving it was real
scrappy until that that that first round
so i mean that's that's the trade-off
though like you don't either your app
makes money and like you can flow and
like kind of live off it or yeah you got
to do that kind of stuff and then
eventually bridge to capital so i was
kind of curious like how yeah
and and to be honest like that wasn't
the only time we had to be scrappy like
even after the first round you know like
a lot of companies we were kind of like
okay
we scaled our user base like i think i
don't know 10x after the seed round but
it still wasn't quite like series a
level so we're kind of stuck in between
rounds and it's like oh [ __ ] back off
payroll
okay like here we go again and you know
it's
there's mo there's been moments multiple
moments like that um and without revenue
it was like you're kind of at the you
know it's it's a safety net right like
it's something you can go back on right
that that that i i i've i've been the
receiver of that advice not not in this
round at building revenue cap but in the
past of the like
just go go and it's it's not bad advice
because it does like that's how
instagram did it right there's examples
of companies that
but it's that classic like you you know
people with a portfolio of tens or
hundreds of companies giving advice to
somebody with a portfolio of one
and like i know
the risk the the the the risk equation
is fundamentally different there right
uh between people and it's just one of
those tensions with venture capital that
exists and like you just got to
negotiate so
um yeah it's it's yeah you know it's a
story we've heard all too much i think
it's why
you know i beat obviously i've got a
horse in the race but like it's why i
think subscriptions are great right
because it just like you can still use
venture capital and in fact like i think
it can be very accelerative right but uh
yeah but like you have options right and
you're like less fragile um
now
i mean and i'm happy to say like after
that grind now we're absolutely the best
place we've ever been we have
you know recurring revenue we have
more cash in the bank than we've ever
had like multiple years of runway and we
should hit cash flow positive like
pretty soon so it's like totally
different ball game and i think
to answer your question we turned on
subscriptions yeah about a year ago and
it really changed the like
perspective of product building too and
i think that's a fundamental difference
like when we were raising our seed round
and you know we had i mean we do we have
a social network on top of our tool and
people were like hey why don't you just
try and get to like a billion users like
that really changes how you build
product and what type of features you
prioritize like yeah you're gonna be
more like okay let me put in another
sharing like let me really nudge you to
share or like eat eyeballs right you
don't care you don't care what's behind
them right you're just yeah like you
basically focus on the top of the funnel
instead of the middle bottom of the
funnel and like the subscriptions right
yeah yeah i mean subscriptions the
bottom bottom of the funnel
and
that's cool because it kind of focus it
focuses you more and that's that was
just a really it was all a big unlock
like last year and you know frankly we
had to figure out how to make money we
were kind of like in between again and
um
yeah it just came to us
david came to us and convinced us to do
revenue yeah i forgot i forgot that that
was the that was the the case i mean
that was you know part of the thesis of
of what we built too was to like
i ideally lowered the barrier and and
and and stuff like that so um
but how has like has has that
because i think there's one that you
kind of mentioned just like
top of funnel versus bottle funnel when
you think of an app that's driven by
virality there's like disadvantages to
reducing right to like yeah so you must
be balancing that really delicately
right because you still you don't want
to you don't want to take the gas out of
that that viral loop yeah
yeah i mean especially a year ago when
we're like oh man we've had a free app
we have like you know 400 000 maus or
whatever it was at the time and we're
about to introduce this like paid
product you know it was kind of
nerve-wracking and how to do that
tastefully but
you know we took the approach where we
didn't pay well any of the current
functionality like you could come in you
could do everything you did before in
fact we upgraded the free functionality
as well and then we built new stuff so
like new vocal effects
uh new ways to like automatically make
your song sound better using algorithms
um and a few other cool things that
people wanted and we paywalled like
additional functionality so i think that
was really crucial to do it that way um
and we spent you know a few extra months
building that but uh that was key and
then people
converted and they're still converting
because it's just like you get the core
experience you come in and then you know
we gradually level them up and we've
launched one subscription product so we
have rapchat gold which again unlocks
the premium creator tools but now we're
working on a second one that we're going
to layer on top that helps these artists
make money and gets their songs on
spotify and apple music and that's going
to kind of complete the artist journey
so
building subscription products can be
like really fun and fulfilling for both
parties you know it's like we're finding
ways to help you in your career
and also like we don't have to
starve either you know it's like we can
both grow together and that probably
sounds too happy but like really it is
like
it's been awesome you know it's almost
like an efficient market right where
people are paying for value there's a
term for the values getting created
right like oh it's almost like a good
you know way of doing commerce like i
like that so tell me a little bit more
about um
about the the fundraising process
um as an app
and kind of being i know you know you
said there was that kind of in-between
time where it's like you
you you had all these signs of product
market fit you were going after the big
opportunity
and then when you switch to
subscriptions it wasn't too long after
that that you you went and raised money
right so
did the subscription product really take
off or was it just
early and signs of it really taking off
that seed investment i when we close
that round you're talking about that's
you know whatever public and um that was
around nico and adjacent came in right
you know we were a couple months into
subscription so it's not like we had a
ton of data uh and we weren't even like
fully rolled out now we had proof that
people
liked it and good conversion rates and
stuff like that but i like i think that
was iteration one of the paywall and
iteration one of the flow and like
like really early uh but i do think it
changed the pers like how
you know investors perceived our company
and we we proactively changed it too
we're like no we're building
subscription products for our best users
and like you know we were able to kind
of take control of the pitch more so
than before where it's like you're not
making money how are you going to make
money are you going to be a social
network with ads or are you going to be
like a tools company it's like nah like
this is this is what we are like you
know and that really put us in control
and
um yeah once we got niko and a few other
like we it was also just a good time in
the market like i feel like in the past
couple years you guys have seen
there's been a lot of activity on the
investors side getting into subscription
apps on the market side with ipos on the
founders side with building really great
apps that scaled i mean at jason's whole
portfolio as an example um so i think
people were also like that was the first
time where the market worked in our
favor
because before we were a music tech
social
you're like you're like uh yeah you're
like instagram but smaller yeah yeah
right like and so
it also like it was kind of a perfect
storm i guess and um yeah we were very
fortunate to get in the right investors
that understood the market and also
understood like the vision like the
vision was a lot clearer um and like i
know nico really latched on to it and
his kind of thesis was perfect for like
what we're doing for music um so yeah it
just it was a good fit and obviously
like sony was in it and like you know
that that was kind of a big key moment
to get validation from like the actual
music industry where it's like oh
they're a lot more open and flexible to
some of these new coming technologies
and apps and companies and in fact like
see value in working together
that kind of knocks down that like
historical music tech graveyard of the
industry killing every music tech
started they learned their lesson once
probably yeah pretty much yeah i'm
really curious about about sony
specifically and then you know you've
already been talking about nika but you
after after raising that round and going
through that process what what's your
perspective and maybe even any advice to
people thinking about this
about that kind of strategic alignment
and the kind of value add
um you know finding that that that
company investor
founder fit any lessons you've learned
from that uh yeah i mean it's hard one
like
i was gonna say i was gonna ask like
what how you because it sounds like your
leverage diff change probably right from
like this first cause i i can't imagine
did you raise those first rounds in ohio
uh yeah
some in ohio some in the midwest couple
you know smaller funds on the coast but
mostly it's kind of changed drastically
since even in those first couple rounds
right like it's gonna be yeah for sure
for sure no we have a lot more left i
mean we can be a lot more cheesy we've
got to pick like really great investors
as of late um it's a whole different
yeah it's been
it's been crazy um crazy awesome but
yeah i mean working
i don't know you'll get a lot of
different advice in working with
strategics or big industry partners and
depending on who you talk to some will
say don't touch them at all some will
say if you can work with them work with
them you know all i can say is from my
experience like it's it's not easy like
you're working with a massive usually a
public company and they have a lot more
process than than you do so like
literally getting a deal done is just
going to take longer be more strenuous
probably have a couple strings we were
fortunate enough for it to be like a
really good like clean same terms type
deal but like um it's it can be really
difficult uh and that's kind of up to
the founder and the company to figure
out like is it worth it um you know for
us
major record labels are like
still kind of the end state for a lot of
potential artists in their journey like
they still provide a lot of value if you
get to that point so like of course we
want to like for the long tail for our
you know millions of creators give them
that opportunity and if we can help
bridge the gap to like get signed at
some point that's really
that's really interesting to us uh but
yeah it's hard and again it's very
contextual it depends on every deal
depends on every company and in general
it's just it's going to take
it's going to take some time yeah
dealing with like a big company like
like sony like adventure deals probably
the only thing you're probably told for
at this stage because like that's a bit
cleaner right like a venture deal it's
like they invest money yeah if you can
get it on the same terms as like another
venture investor like it keeps it clean
versus like if you're working on
partnerships or something like that it
gets more complicated and i think those
differences and i'm sure i'm sure that's
probably something you're thinking about
going forward is like how do you
actually like begin to really engage on
those partnerships i think that's even
harder so yeah in this specific case or
like maybe a more general case like a
venture a small like venture investment
can be like a nice way to kind of just
like get your foot in the door with with
a company or like a strategic
just kind of meet people just kind of
give them some visibility
and then as you grew up but i would be i
would i would caution against like
trying to engage on some big hairy
strategic like partnership deal i would
like push that out until you get a bit
bigger and like you said like can match
the like the bandwidth differences a
little bit better yeah have like our own
general counsel yeah our partnerships
personally like you need somebody to run
partnerships right or the ceo's main job
right like yeah and that might probably
not the best use of your time at this
stage right so no i totally agree i mean
that's that's that's pretty spot-on and
how did you even get an intro i mean if
you don't mind sharing like it seems
like it is such a perfect fit but even
those perfect fits like sometimes it's
hard to just even get your foot in the
door email ceo sony yeah right can we
get a zoom call
honestly like that's uh
[ __ ] i don't even know i mean i think
someone might have intro to us uh or
i i reached out to somebody uh i mean
we've had a lot of different contacts i
mean over the years and and you guys
know this but like
now okay we've been startups for five
six years and
have pretty good network and investors
partners founders
and it's just kind of a flywheel like
now you know things come in things go
out like
it's kind of an engine i think with that
one it was later on in my like startup
journey so i had a lot of kind of
connections out there already with the
other major labels too it's like you
know we we've talked to we've kept in
touch that was one thing i think we've
done really well throughout like our
time even though we've you know we've
been around for a minute but we've
consistently like kept people updated
whether it's investors whether it's
potential employees whether it's
partners and you know sometimes like the
guy you knew or a girl or whoever
four years ago that you were talking to
at a specific part of a bigger company
is now leading venture right like and
that that type of stuff happens a lot
and
i don't think this is one of those
instances like i literally think we
talked to one division of sony and then
someone like introduced us to another
like oh you should talk to the us music
department or whatever and um
you know
all that to say like it's just happens
like you just reach out to people or
people reach out to you there's there's
no like magic forms these big places
have venture teams typically yeah or
they have like some adventure part of
their corp dev wing that's like um has
you know funds and and knows what
they're doing usually um but but yeah i
mean it's tricky too to like pick
partners like because yeah you also like
we're we're a um interesting company in
this inside like we have kind of many
implicit partners right yeah right um
you know there's no like there's no like
cap table
you know wedding rings between any of us
which
maybe simplifies or doesn't i thought
you guys owned like 10 percent of rap
chat yeah
yeah that was that was that's how you
got our free plan
right in the early days you didn't read
the full you didn't read the entire
terms of service
sorry parody parody comedy hey i did i
did want to ask facebook
kind of fuss jumped into your space not
too long ago where were you
because you we guarantee you you
remember when you saw this but what were
you doing when like you saw like
facebook like cloned you guys i i
honestly think i might have been sitting
right here like i think i was just
working
it was nothing special like that's like
a founder moment like there's these
moments where you're like oh somebody
just like a bullet just grazed my ear
yeah
no i wish i could say i was like at the
gym on the treadmill and then it came in
and i like jumped off the treadmill
statistically it's most likely you're
sitting at your desk but yeah
statistically yeah
no it was
it was kind of a weird like i don't i
don't even know how to describe the
emotions i mean i was just like i kind
of laughed it was just like okay
you know i i definitely wasn't um
like scared or super worried or freaking
out like you know it's maybe
i don't know 2019 me or something or in
the early days would have been like oh
[ __ ] like now i can't get venture
funding or now i can't like keep
building like they're gonna crush it but
i mean we've been around and cemented
ourselves so yeah i just it was kind of
funny and ironic and then it went like
many viral on twitter with a lot of you
know my network and other people and
then um i had friends sending it to me
like oh dude what do you gotta do and
i'm just like
i don't know man like just probably
download it and see how bad it is and go
from there
yeah and it was
and honestly it was just kind of a fun
thing like you know it it did like we
got press around the round and then some
people could you know write about that
and it was kind of a funny story and
somewhat of a badge of honor like people
you know they copy a lot of
the top apps and again it's just kind of
like validation that like
clearly you're onto something i mean
they use the same
color scheme
emojis at okay one of my most proud
things that's the stuff that makes you
angry right as a founder it's not that
they cloned you it's that they stole the
little details right that's what makes
me mad the thing that really got me was
like for our like button right uh it's a
flame it's like an emoji and like when
you hit it it like turns into the actual
emoji flame and i always thought that
was like the sickest thing ever like
they did the same exact thing i was just
like all right like i mean that's what
the little things are what confirmed
that they actually kind of like really
looked at your your app but um no it's
been
i don't even know what they've been up
to i don't even know if they shipped
updates it's
zero concern to us and i think um it was
just kind of fun it was like funny to
share with the team and uh investors and
you know a lot of investors are like
hell yeah like that's a good sign like
keep going and you should hire somebody
off that team yeah right
oh trust me i would love to cause like
just think about like yeah i i think
you've got the right mentality about it
i'm not even telling you this is like
trying to make you feel better
because like think how much more skin in
the game you have and i don't know who
built this it's probably some product
managers like promotion packet project
or whatever i'm being condescending to
people working big companies but you
know
but but but think about it like this you
know this is a this is a one-time thing
they're trying out right this is your
passion right this is your life yes
whatever years right like good luck
unless unless they just happen to be way
more talented and way more funded which
maybe facebook is but like they're not
they don't execute perfectly on
everything right so i just think you
just smile and you just feel like yeah
let's go right it's not it's not like
apple's competing with you and being
like we're pre-installing a chat rap app
right
on the phone which you know could happen
yeah i appreciate that i mean the thing
is also like look in the early days we
were i'm just sharing this for context
like we were you know one of the first
apps that actually let you record your
voice over a beat and share it like that
was like new okay now there's plenty of
apps where you can come in record vocals
or you know different types of audio
over beats and like music making apps
are kind of a commodity um but what
we've done that i mentioned and we kind
of fell into this was like we built that
social layer that community layer and
you can't replicate that you know like
they can come in and replicate the tool
and have a feed but like nah dude we
already have like hundreds of thousands
of like passionate creators have been
with us that have been riding with us
and my favorite thing was when complex
tweeted it out and like complex being
like a very like cultural industry
outlet and they tweeted out and the
responses of that were just like
the most hilarious thing i don't think i
could say like half of it but it was
like basically like zuck this like
reptile coming into like you know
vulture culture vulture and like all
[ __ ] that like would be my worst
nightmare people said about us and they
don't like it's just
we're authentic and you know we really
care about the community and that's you
know that's number one that's awesome
well i think that's a great place to
wrap up we're coming up to the top of
the hour but i did want to give you a
few seconds to uh to pitch
yeah i know you're hiring and you got a
lot going on right now um any any
specific roles at the company that uh
that you think our audience might be a
great fit for
yeah for sure i appreciate that um i
mean really just like product builders
and i say that like broadly so engineers
designers uh
growth marketers um we're looking for
really great people to help us scale
again we're still a small team
10 people
fully remote and
you know really looking to scale the
product and the company and um now that
we have some stability it's a great time
to jump on board and uh
yeah i mean we really like you know we
really think that
uh
this era of mass music creation has
begun and we kind of kick-started it but
we're only getting started right and um
we just have you know a really strong
opportunity to provide you know the
everyday stack for the everyday artists
and that's that's our passion yeah
that's amazing i took a look at your
careers page it looks like there's some
great opportunities there
across the whole stack which is fun so
yeah which position were you looking at
david
[Laughter]
you guys are welcome to have this
conversation but just let me leave the
room please
i mean i do have a background in uh
recording audio engineering it does
yes that's true
no i'm not in the market i have too much
fun having conversations like this with
uh people like you said all right thank
you for listening to some podcasts
no that's a great place to go out on
that thank you so much seth for being on
the podcast and man it's been great
you've been so uh generous with your
your time and just sharing and um you
know seth's been on multiple other
podcasts he's been on uh app promotion
summit and so the you know
i love it when people in the space are
open and share about the successes the
failures how they're building things so
thanks for your time today and for being
so active in the kind of broader
app maker community yeah no i mean and i
just want to say thanks thanks for you
guys uh the podcast is awesome i
listened to it uh every episode and
yeah not to plug your your product but
your product like you know we
love it and it's been instrumental in
building a uh a real business over here
so we're
really excited and yeah i just just
appreciate you guys getting dusty in
here yeah
thanks great to meet you
yeah likewise man let's let's hang out
so let's do it you guys take care
to make sure you never miss an episode
subscribe to the show and your favorite
podcast player thanks so much for
listening until next time
[Music]